byside.com 2017-05-03

# BySide

## Privacy policy

### BySide Platform Privacy policy

BySide is committed to respect and protect your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the BySide Platform and governs data collection, management, processing and usage, including (but not limited to) that which is:

  * generated and collected on our websites,

  * generated and collected through our customers sites,

  * generated and handled internally at BySide.

We protect your privacy and our objectives are to be transparent about how we process your personal data.

Any concerns or comments about this policy and questions about deleting or correcting your personal data should directed to our support team at dataprotection@byside.com

Note: if any BySide customer links in their website to this “Privacy Policy”, it’s automatically assumed they comply to any statement expressed in this policy.

### Fundamental principles

  * We do not process personal data unless we need it to deliver our products and services or to run our company efficiently.

  * We don’t share your personal information (without your consent) with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products or services or protect our rights.

  * We don’t store personal information on servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our products or services.

  * We don’t own any information collected by our service and platform in our customers Website. By contract all end users data collected by our platform in our customers service belongs exclusively to our customers. BySide cannot use any of there customers end users data unless with explicit written consent or for global, non personal service indicators and reports.

  * We do use cookies and other similar tools to help us collect and store information about you and other users of our products and services.

For more information about cookies, please check our cookie policy here.

### Data ownership and responsibility

All data collected by the BySide Platform or service in BySide customers websites belongs exclusively to BySide customers.

BySide cannot use any of there customers end users data unless with explicit written consent or instructions or for global, non personal, service indicators and reports.

All BySide customers are legally responsible for actions or registrations needed for any local or global Data Protection Acts like, for Portuguese customers, law nº 67/98, de 26 de Outubro, or Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), for United Kingdom.

All needed registers should be handled by BySide Customers in the proper local Data Protection Entity.

As an example, for Portugal:

CNPD - Comissão Nacional de Protecção de Dados  
Rua de São Bento, nº148 - 3º (Tel: 21 392 84 00)  
1200-821 LISBOA

BySide cannot, in any situation, be declared responsible for any fault or error of their customers in any step needed with the proper local or global data protection entities.

### Collection of your Personal Information

BySide collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. BySide also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites. 

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by BySide. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by BySide for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, to provide general statistics regarding and may be also used to personalize, improve and empower BySide cutovers websites allowing them to deliver better products and experience to their customers. 

BySide encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from BySide, or that use BySide service, so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. BySide is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the BySide and BySide family of Web sites, including any BySide customer website. 

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through BySide public message boards, chat services or any other public communication service, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: BySide does not read any of your private online communications.

### Use of your Personal Information

In order to improve your journey in BySide customers Websites and provide you the right content and actions, we analyze your entire journey on the website and may collect and use your personal information to deliver the services and content you are looking for. BySide may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from BySide, BySide customers and its affiliates. BySide may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. 

BySide does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists or any collected information to third parties. BySide may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, BySide may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to BySide, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

BySide does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent. 

BySide keeps track of the it’s customers Web sites visited pages in order to determine what services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within BySide Customers Websites to it’s end users whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

BySide will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on BySide or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of BySide; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of BySide, or the public. 

### Use of Cookies

The BySide Service use "cookies" to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize BySide pages, or register with BySide site or services, a cookie helps BySide to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Web site, the information you previously provided may be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the BySide services or Web sites you visit. 

For more information, please check our cookie policy here. 

### Security of your Personal Information

BySide secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. BySide secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

### Your rights

You have the right to ask us, for BySide Website, or to any of BySide customers (in this case, your should ask our customers directly) not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.

You can exercise your right to prevent your data processing by ticking certain boxes on the forms we, or our customers, use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [dataprotection@byside.com](mailto:dataprotection@byside.com).

We want to ensure that any personal information we hold about you is correct and you have a right to ask us to update our records or delete any personal information we, or out customers, hold about you (although we may need to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes).

### Access to information 

You the right to access information we hold about you. You simply need to comply with legal protection laws to obtain information about you from us. We may need to charge you a fee of 15€ to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. Thank you for your understanding.

Please be aware that we are under no obligation to store personal information indefinitely and disclaim any liability arising out of, or related to, the destruction of such personal information. In addition, please note we do not keep personal information for longer than is necessary but that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases without some residual data because of backups and other reasons. We will however ensure that your personal information is ‘put beyond use’ in that we will not be able, or will not attempt, to use such personal information to make any decision which will affect you, we will not give any other organisation access to such personal information and we will surround your personal information with appropriate technical and organisational security in line with this policy.

### Changes to this Statement

BySide will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. BySide encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how BySide is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed, and should be addressed to our a/c Data Protection Compliance Manager

BySide  
Rua Visconde Bóbeda, 70   
4000-108 Porto - Portugal

Or by emailing [dataprotection@byside.com](mailto:dataprotection@byside.com).
